lottoland.com.au 2018-11-24

# Privacy Policy - Lottoland Australia - Lottoland.com.au

##  1 General 

1.1 References to "Lottoland.com.au", "Lottoland", “Lottoland Australia”, "us", "our" and "we" in Privacy Policy are references to Lottoland (Australia) Pty Ltd (ACN 602 590 429), a company registered under the _Corporations Act 2001_ (Cth) and licensed by the Northern Territory to accept wagers by telephone and the internet on a global basis. 

1.2 References to "customer", "you" and "your" in this Privacy Policy are references to a person aged 18 years or older who has opened an account with Lottoland ("Lottoland Account") and/or submitted your information to us. 

1.3 This Privacy Policy describes the way in which we deal with certain information and data you provide to us to enable us to manage your relationship with Lottoland. 

1.4 This Privacy Policy is in addition to our General Terms and Conditions and should be read in conjunction with such. 

1.5 Customers must be aged 18 years or older in order to hold a Lottoland account and to place bets. It is an offence for anyone under the age of 18 to place a bet or register a Lottoland Account in an attempt to place a bet. If children, or any minors, use your computer, we suggest that you restrict access to the website through the use of filtering software (for example, Net Nanny). 

1.6 For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, 'Personal Information' means information or an opinion (including information or an opinion forming part of a database), whether true or not, and whether recorded in a material form or not, about an individual whose identity is apparent, or can reasonably be ascertained, from the information or opinion. 

1.7 In this Privacy Policy, a reference to 'Australian Privacy Principles' or APPs means the Australian Privacy Principles contained in the _Privacy Act 1988_ (Cth). 

1.8 We will process any Personal Information provided to us (whether via the Lottoland website at Lottoland.com.au (the "Website") or by any other means specified in this Privacy Policy) or otherwise held by us relating to you, in the manner set out in this Privacy Policy. 

1.9 Acceptance: You agree that, by opening a Lottoland Account, by submitting your information to us and/or by placing bets with us, you accept and agree to be bound by the terms of this Privacy Policy and you confirm your consent to the use or disclosure of your Personal Information as: 

###  (a) set out in this Privacy Policy; ****

###  (b) clearly explained to you at the time when the information is collected from you; or ****

###  (c) permitted under the _Privacy Act 1988_ (Cth) and the Australian Privacy Principles. ****

1.10 If you do not agree with the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Website or otherwise provide us with your Personal Information. 

1.11 This Privacy Policy does not apply to websites which are linked to our Website and over which we have no control. 

1.12 We reserve the right to change, amend and add to this Privacy Policy at any time, with any such amendments being displayed on our Website. Where practicable, we will endeavour to notify you of any amendments by email, SMS or other means. Your continued use of the Lottoland Website or your Lottoland Account or your continued placement of bets following any such amendments will constitute acceptance of the amended Privacy Policy. It is your responsibility to make yourself aware of any amendments. 

##  2 Collection 

2.1 We only collect Personal Information to the extent that it is required for our business activities and only by lawful and fair means that are not unreasonably intrusive. 

2.2 The information and data about you which we may collect, use process and disclose includes, but is not limited to, the following: 

###  (a) information that you provide to us by filling in forms on the Website (including your name, phone contact details, address and email address) or any other information you submit to us via the Website, mail, telephone, email or other means; 

###  (b) records of correspondence, whether via the Website, email, telephone or other means; 

###  (c) your responses to surveys or customer research that we carry out; 

###  (d) Your financial information (such as credit card/debit card information) and details of the transactions you carry out with us, whether via your Lottoland Account, the Website, telephone or other means; 

###  (e) information that has been collected from third parties (including but not limited to, information from financial institutions or law enforcement agencies or regulatory authorities) to assist in the verification of your identity; and 

###  (f) details of your visits to the Website including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data 

2.3 From time to time, you may be able to deal with us anonymously or by pseudonym. However, if you do not provide us with certain personal information, we may not be able to provide you with the service and product that you seek. 

##  3 Use and Disclosure 

3.1 We may use your Personal Information and data together with other information for the purposes of: 

###  (a) identifying you; 

###  (b) processing your bets, including card and on-line payments; 

###  (c) setting up, operating and managing your account; 

###  (d) complying with our legal and regulatory duties; 

###  (e) building up personal profiles; 

###  (f) carrying out customer research, surveys and analyses; 

###  (g) providing you with information about promotional offers and our products and services, where you have consented; 

###  (h) monitoring transactions for the purposes of preventing fraud, irregular betting, money laundering and cheating or detecting suspicious behaviour; 

###  (i) our internal business purposes (such as internal accounting or management processes); 

###  (j) determining your liability to Australian GST and other taxes where applicable; 

###  (k) providing you with the products and services you have requested; and 

###  (l) meeting any purpose for which the information was submitted. 

3.2 We do not sell your Personal Information to third parties. 

3.3 We may disclose your Personal Information to third parties (including other companies within our corporate group of companies, business partners, successors in title to our business, suppliers that are engaged to process such information on our behalf, law enforcement or investigative agencies, regulators (including racing or control bodies and sporting organisations), and other government or statutory authorities or departments): 

###  (a) to the extent necessary, to provide the services you have requested or to meet the purpose for which your personal information was submitted; 

###  (b) if we have informed you of the particular third party to whom your personal information will be disclosed, at the time of collection; 

###  (c) in order to participate in activities with business partners, who will be identified to you when the relevant personal information is collected; 

###  (d) to help us make credit decisions; 

###  (e) to check your age and identity; 

###  (f) for fraud and money laundering prevention and for lawful purposes associated with the conduct of our business; 

###  (g) if the disclosure is: 

####  (i) permitted by law; 

####  (ii) permitted by the Australian Privacy Principles; 

####  (iii) necessary to co-operate with the judicial process of a law enforcement agency or lawful investigations of a law investigative agency; 

####  (iv) necessary to protect and defend the rights or property of Lottoland, our Website, or partner websites; or 

####  (v) necessary to lessen, prevent or detect unlawful activity or serious threats to individuals, public health or safety or the integrity of any sporting or other event. 

3.4 We are entitled to share the information we hold on you, which includes Personal Information, data and betting history, with the Northern Territory Racing Commission or any other statutory authorities, sporting bodies and other bodies, including the police, in order to investigate fraud, money laundering or sports integrity issues and to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations. 

3.5 In order to comply with Lottoland's legal and regulatory requirements and Lottoland's own internal risk management procedures, we will retain information for a period of time (generally not more than six years) after closure of your account. All such information will be held in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

3.6 From time to time, we may send you marketing materials such as newsletters or promotional offers about our products and services. If you do not wish to receive any communications about our products and services, company information and updates or promotional offers and surveys, you can opt out by: 

###  (a) Changing your Lottoland Account preferences under the “My Account” section of the Website, 

###  (b) Clicking the “Unsubscribe” link of the bottom of any email; or 

###  (c) following the “Unsubscribe” instructions at the end of each SMS message. ****

3.7 If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you may do so by clicking the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of each email. However, please be aware that this applies to marketing and promotional material only, as we are required by law to still send you certain essential information, such as activity statements and updates on your Lottoland Account. 

##  4 Overseas Disclosure of Personal Information 

4.1 Given that the Internet is a global environment, using the Internet to collect, disclose and process personal data (which may amount to Personal Information) necessarily involves the disclosure of data on an international basis. 

4.2 From time to time, we may disclose the Personal Information you provide to trusted third parties both outside of Australia. Such a disclosure of data does not take place unless: 

###  (a) Lottoland reasonably believes that the recipient of Personal Information outside Australia is subject to principles of fair handling that are substantially similar to the Australian Privacy Principles; or 

###  (b) the transfer is to a trusted third party, including but not limited to, our related companies (such as our parent company Lottoland Holdings Ltd), our professional advisers including lawyers and accountants, law enforcement bodies, courts of law or as otherwise required or authorised by law, regulatory or governmental bodies; or 

###  (c) you consent to the transfer at the time of providing the relevant Personal Information; or 

###  (d) the transfer is necessary for the performance of a contract between you and Lottoland, or for the implementation of pre-contractual measures taken in response to a request by you; or 

###  (e) the transfer is necessary for the conclusion or performance of a contract concluded in your interest between Lottoland and a third party; or 

###  (f) all of the following apply: 

####  (i) the transfer is for your benefit; 

####  (ii) it is impracticable to obtain your consent to the transfer; and 

####  (iii) if it were practicable to obtain such consent, you would be likely to give it. ****

4.3 Please be aware that countries outside of Australia may not always have the same or similar privacy and data protection laws. However, where we do disclose your Personal Information to parties outside of Australia, Lottoland takes steps as are reasonable in the circumstances as to ensure that the information which it has been disclosed is used in accordance with this Privacy Policy and will not be held, used or disclosed by the recipient of the information inconsistently with the Australian Privacy Principles. 

4.4 Important Notice to the Customer: 

In the event that the use or processing of your personal information involves the disclosure of any information outside Australia, you acknowledge and accept that by providing us with your personal information, you consent to such overseas disclosure. By consenting to such disclosure, you acknowledge and accept that: 

###  (a) you will not hold Lottoland accountable under the _Privacy Act 1988,_

###  (b) you will not be able to seek redress under the _Privacy Act 1988_ against Lottoland for any breach of your privacy by an overseas recipient. 

4.5 If and when the Personal Information you provide to us is disclosed to parties outside of Australia for the purpose of this Privacy Policy or for other purposes approved by you, these recipients are most likely to be located in counties listed in the Appendix to this Policy. This list of counties is not exhaustive and may change from time to time. 

##  5 Information storage 

5.1 We will take such steps as are reasonable in the circumstances to ensure that your Personal Information is kept secure and is protected from misuse, loss, unauthorised access, modification and disclosure. However, by providing us with your Personal Information and continuing to use our Website and services, you agree and acknowledge that you are responsible for ensuring the security details and passwords relevant to your Lottoland Account are kept confidential, and that Lottoland cannot be liable for any information obtained by outside parties from your continued use of this Website. 

5.2 By its nature, we cannot guarantee that information transmitted on the internet is 100% secure. Accordingly, we cannot guarantee your absolute privacy from any hypertext on our Website leading to other Websites. We encourage you to be careful providing information to any third parties other than Lottoland. 

##  6 Telephone Calls 

6.1 Telephone calls to and from our Customer Contact Centre are recorded in order to meet our legal and regulatory obligations as well as for training and security purposes. This includes recording all bets, queries and disputes. These recordings or details of these calls may be disclosed to law enforcement agencies, regulators and other government departments as part of our legal and regulatory obligations. 

##  7 Non-Personal Information 

7.1 We may collect and use non-Personal Information associated with your use of our Website for tracking information, statistics and marketing purposes. The non-personal information we obtain assists us in monitoring and administering our Website and improving our service. 

##  8 Use of Cookies 

8.1 We may use cookies as a means of collecting information from a web server for the above purposes following a customer's use of the Website. If you register with us or if you continue to use the Website you agree to our use of cookies. 

8.2 Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive, which allows websites to recognise your user preferences and other information. They help us to improve the Website and to deliver a better and more personalised service. Some of the cookies we use are essential for the Website to operate. 

8.3 If you want to delete any cookies already stored on your computer or stop the cookies that keep track of your browsing patterns on the Website, you can do so by deleting your existing cookies and/or altering your browser's privacy settings to block cookies (the process you follow will differ from browser to browser). If you would like more information on how to do this please visit http://www.allaboutcookies.org/. Please note that deleting our cookies or disabling our future cookies means that you may not be able to access certain areas or features of the Website. 

##  9 Accessing and Correcting your Personal Information 

9.1 We will take such steps as are reasonable in the circumstances to ensure that Personal Information we collect, hold, use and disclose is accurate, complete and up-to-date. In order to maintain the accuracy of your Personal Information, we rely on the quality of information you provide us. 

9.2 You are entitled to access and correct the information held about you. There are some exceptions specified by law where we may refuse your request. However, if one of these circumstances applies, we will provide you with a written explanation of the reasons for refusal, unless it would be unreasonable to provide such notice. 

9.3 If you wish to access and/or correct the information we hold about you, this can be done by contacting us using the contact details provided under section 12 "Contact Us" of this Privacy Policy. 

9.4 We will endeavour to respond to your request within a reasonable time. We may also charge reasonable costs for responding to the request. 

##  10 Complaints about Privacy 

10.1 If you have concerns that your privacy has been compromised or have any other privacy-related complaints, please contact us at the details below with your concern. 

10.2 We will then investigate your complaint or query and endeavour to provide you with our response within a reasonable time. 

10.3 If, after receiving our response, you still consider your privacy complaint remains unresolved, you may then, for example, take your complaint to the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner. 

##  11 Disclaimer 

11.1 To the extent that this Privacy Policy exceeds the minimum obligations of Lottoland under Commonwealth and State and Territory legislation, this Privacy Policy serves as a documentation of our voluntarily self-imposed standards. While we are determined to meet those standards as best we can, to the extent permitted by law, Lottoland is not liable if it does not adhere to any of these voluntarily self-imposed standards for any loss, liability, costs, expense or damage arising as a result of Lottoland failing to meet any of the voluntarily self-imposed standards in this Privacy Policy. 

##  12 Contact Us 

12.1 If you have any enquiries please do not hesitate to contact our customer services team by sending an email to: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
